# Sean Kim

dev.seakim@gmail.com | 201-850-7923 | LinkedIn: seankhkim | Github: seakim | https://www.SeanKim.life

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A diligent and goal-driven full-stack junior developer with an emphasis on Frontend Development with React. With over 3+ years experience in client facing technical support, goal is to provide intuitive solution integrating development to help maximize growth. Entrepreneurial, detail-oriented leader with the ability to build sophisticated web applications from mockup to deployment.

#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

<u>Languages:</u>
Javascript, Ruby, HTML5, CSS3

<u>Frameworks & Libraries:</u>
Node.js, Express.js, React, Redux,
Rails, JQuery, SASS

<u>Databases & Other Tools:</u>
MongoDB, SQL, Github, Heroku,
Firebase, RESTful API

#### **CONCEPTS**

Git Workflow, Agile Development, MVC design pattern, Data-Structure & Algorithms

#### RECENT PROJECT HIGHLIGHTS

## Sole Contributor | Ticketing / Dashboard page at BlackRock Tech: Hub in NY Office

- Integrates with HP Service Manager. With API Post calls, It significantly reduces time to create each ticket from **2 minutes** to **10 seconds**.
- Tracks users' technical issues and trends and displays daily/weekly/monthly/yearly views in dashboard.
  - o Full-Stack, MySQL, Express, Node, handlebars, JQuery, HP Service Manager API

## Full-stack Developer & Application Structure Designer | Test Jotter (Team project - group of two)

- Provides productivity for Software Testers
  - o Full-Stack, MongoDB, Express, Node, React, Redux, Google OAuth
  - Project URL: <a href="https://pure-reaches-15864.herokuapp.com/">https://pure-reaches-15864.herokuapp.com/</a>
  - o Github Link: https://github.com/You-need-to-test/testcase-jotter

## Sole Contributor | NYTimes Search

- Searches "The New York Times" articles and saves to favorite page.
  - o Full-Stack, MongoDB, Express, Node, React NYTimes API
  - Project URL: <a href="https://polar-oasis-76040.herokuapp.com/">https://polar-oasis-76040.herokuapp.com/</a>
  - Github Link: <a href="https://github.com/seakim/NYTimes">https://github.com/seakim/NYTimes</a>

## Product Manager & Developer | Lunch Finder (Team project - group of four)

- Recommends lunch near you directly instead of searching restaurants.
  - Front-End, Google map API, Yelp API, Edamam API

#### **EMPLOYMENT**

Mar 2015 - Current New York, NY

## IT Analyst II | BlackRock

- Maintain all client based technology and provide technical support for NY and other regional offices on the East Coast in the United States.
- Work with large amount of tickets for 2800+ users in NY, ranging from Analysts to Managing Directors in all departments, on both remote and in-person basis.
- Thrive in a fast-paced environment where multitasking is essential.
- Prioritize, research, troubleshoot, and resolve escalated technical issues.

Jan - Mar 2015 New Providence, NJ

## **Resource Tech** | Summit Medical Group

• Provided services pertaining to hardware / software installation and troubleshooting for Windows migration project.

Jul 2013 - Mar 2015 Palisades Park. NJ

### **Fitness Trainer** | Fitness Factory

• Evaluated and assisted clients in achieving personal fitness goals.

Jan - May 2014 Union, NJ

## **Department Tutor** | Kean University

• Tutored on All undergraduate levels of Math and basic levels of Computer Science.

#### **EDUCATION**

2018

Jersey City, NJ

## Javascript Full Stack Development | Rutgers University Extension

- Completed intensive 24 week on site boot camp dedicated to designing and building web applications.
- Obtained the average grade of A+ based on 23 individual/team projects.
- Learned skills include:
  - o HTML5, CSS3, Handlebars, Javascript, Node, Express, MongoDB, SQL, React

2014 Union, NJ

## B.A. in Mathematical Science & Minor in Computer Science | Kean University

- Graduated with magna cum laude (GPA 3.70) and Dean's Honors List.
- Completed courseworks include:
  - Computer Organization and Programming, Data Structure, Assembly Language, IT Project Management
  - Calculus I, II, III, IV, Differential Equations, Linear Algebra, Euclidean / Non-Euclidean Geometry, Probability / Statistics, Regression Analysis, Applied Statistics I, II, Statistical methods for Analyzing Data
  - Economics I, II, Accounting I, Corporate Finance I

#### **CERTIFICATIONS & EXAMS**

June 2017 April 2017 March 2017	Certified Jamf Server Admin (CJA)   JAMF Certified Casper Admin (CCA)   JAMF Certified Casper Tech (CCT)   JAMF
June 2014 March 2014	Financial Mathematics Exam (passed)   Society of Actuaries Probability Exam (passed)   Society of Actuaries
June 2013	Certified Personal Trainer   National Academy of Sports Medicine